ANGELA GARCIA-LAVIN

agarcialavin@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/angelagarcialavin | 817.372.6320 | Fort Worth, TX

SUMMARY

10 years' experience providing learning experience design, curriculum & campaign development, project management, and needs analysis & evaluation for global learning strategies. 15 years' experience consulting and developing campaign solutions for executive clients.18 years' designing & developing professional impactful media for marketing and education.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon Workforce Staffing

10/2021 - Present

Learning Leader, Sr. Instructional Designer

- Leading the design and development of global workforce staffing learning experiences
- Consulting with executive leadership to determine learning needs, build and execute learning strategies and measure ROI for training programs.
- Developing processes for efficiency and standardizing production of learning experiences Achievements:
 - Strategize and build blended learning curriculum to integrate soft skills into processbased learning for authentic learning and increased behavioral change.
 - o Responsible for curriculum receiving highest completion rates and ratings in surveys

GM Financial 9/2016 – 10/2021

Manager of Learning & Development

- Collaborated cross-functionally to lead global learning programs.
- Led instructional design team in the creation of instructor-led, online, remote, virtual instructor-led, e-learning and blended learning experiences.
- Diagnosed learning needs through consulting, needs analysis and assessment.
- Championed authentic learning experiences in support of company culture.

Achievements:

- Challenged current learning structures by introducing animation and remote blended learning modalities in a predominantly instructor-led environment
- Developed and deployed global training solutions to support diversity, equity and inclusion, company culture, compliance, working remotely and return to work initiatives
- Developed efficiency standards and benchmarks for development and delivery of learning experiences globally as well as consistency in branding standards by program and/or curriculum

Various Districts 7/2011 – 9/2016

Educator: Curriculum Development

- Designed and developed curriculum for bilingual learners across a variety of media to increase retention and engagement
- Technology integration to increase learner engagement and supplement curriculum
- Developed personalized learning solutions based on needs analysis and assessment Achievements:
 - Guest Speaker: CISD Peer-to-Peer Training Sessions 2012, 2013 & 2014
 - Guest Speaker: FWISD Annual Technology in Education Conference 2014 & 2015

USHEALTH Group 5/2006 – 6/2011

Art Director & Sr. Copywriter

- Developed marketing collateral campaigns and implemented cost-saving design strategies
- Led the creative team in the design of promotional, communications, advertising and convention print collateral.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with various departments to streamline the design process. Achievements:
 - o Innovative brochure design leading to cost savings of over \$100k in printing costs
 - Award winning collateral design for campaigns
 - o Introduction and implementation of digital resources for online presence

EDUCATION

University of Missouri-Columbia

- Education Specialist: Online Learning Expected Graduation 2022
- Master of Education: Learning Technologies & Design Graduation 2019
- Bachelor of Journalism: Advertising Design Graduation 2002

CERTIFICATES

- Learning Experience Design (NovoEd) 2021
- Creating and Inclusive Environment (DDI) 2021
- Agile Leadership Cohort (Agile Coach Dr. Dave Cornelius) 2021
- DEI Emerging Leaders Certificate (National Diversity & Leadership Conference) 2021
- Designing Virtual Training (Association for Talent Development) 2019
- Flawless Consulting (Designed Learning) 2018
- Microlearning for Disruptive Results (Vignettes Learning) 2018
- Contagious Culture Workshop (Anese Cavanaugh) 2018
- Best Speaker, Best Table Topics & Best Evaluator (Toastmasters) 2017-2019

LANGUAGES

- Fluent native English
- Fluent native Spanish